Subtitles created by AZEVARJ FFC 1902.
Synced for DCP Webrip.
OK.
Sangue, sangue, sangue! E morte.
Muito bem, sabe de uma coisa? Você está se aproveitando demais da situação.
Além disso, acho que conseguimos. Acho que conseguimos.
Conseguimos colocar lá em cima. Obrigado, Yakety-yak!
Você explicou tudo de forma brilhante.
Eu emoldurei o Coração de Leão. Posso emoldurar você também.
É a minha palavra contra a sua.
Na verdade...
E eu vou dardejar todos os predadores de Zootopia para que continue assim.
É a sua palavra contra a sua.
Isso se chama malandragem, querida.
Boom.
Uma dupla improvável, Judy Hopps, a primeira policial coelha da cidade,
e Nicholas Wilde, uma raposa de rua de pouca importância,
Hoje foi descoberta uma conspiração do prefeito Bellwether usando uma caneta gravadora em forma de cenoura de brinquedo.
Eu também posso te enquadrar.
Mais tarde, Wilde também se juntou à ZPD, onde a dupla agora é a primeira...
Dupla coelho-raposa na história de Zootopia.
O novo prefeito e ex-ator Brian Winddancer elogiou os dois.
durante as comemorações do centenário da invenção das paredes climáticas de Zootopia
que permitiu que todos os ambientes e todos os animais coexistissem em uma mesma cidade.
Este é o nosso Zootennial.
E se um coelho humilde do campo e uma raposa astuta e provavelmente criminosa...
podem ignorar suas imensas diferenças e acabar de vez com o preconceito e os estereótipos.
então talvez todos possamos abraçar o nosso
diferenças e ser melhor juntos.
Vamos desvendar um novo caso e tornar o mundo um lugar melhor.
E sejam os melhores parceiros de todos os tempos!
Quer dizer, não somos tão diferentes assim.
Na ZPD, a parceria é a pedra angular do sucesso.
Quer prender os bandidos?
Estejam em sintonia todos os dias.
O vilão de hoje é este inspetor alfandegário.
que tem contrabandeado carga ilegal do exterior através do estaleiro da cidade.
Os capitães Hoggbottom e Truffler estarão no comando.
Higgins, Bloats, flanco esquerdo, Chèvre, Bücheron, direita,
- e bem no meio, os Zebros. - Zebros!
Hopps e Wilde, eu sei que vocês estão ansiosos para provar o seu valor,
Mas, como novatos, vocês apenas observarão e verão as equipes veteranas mostrarem como se faz.
Chefe, olá.
Se você está procurando por Nick e Judy.
Eles disseram que conseguiram! E já estão no local com o bebê!
Tem certeza de que isso vai funcionar?
Foi você quem disse que precisávamos de uma prisão.
Apenas siga o meu exemplo, ok? Aja naturalmente.
- Ei! - Vamos lá.
Olá!
Toda esta área é restrita. Você não pode estar aqui.
Uau. Raposa e coelho.
- Certo... - Sim, mas primeiro os pais orgulhosos, Sr...
Inspetor. Inspetor Snootley.
Inspetor?
O que você faz?
Garantir que nada ilegal seja contrabandeado para cá em um desses contêineres de carga?
Essa é uma maneira estranha de perguntar isso.
Enfim, você precisa ir embora.
Você não pode estar aqui!
- Ah... - Espere. Espere.
Ele tem razão, droga!
O senhor tem razão.
Acho que devíamos ter pensado melhor nisso. Não é, amor?
Antes de decidirmos vir até este belo estaleiro industrial,
Para celebrar o grande dia do nosso aniversariante.
É aniversário dele?
Sim, o primeiro desde...
Desde o acidente.
E sabe qual era o único desejo desse pestinha?
aside from one day getting his tail reattached, yeah,
was to see a choo-choo.
And to maybe get a toot-toot conductor to sign his cast.
But I'm betting a customs inspector would be even better.
Really?
All right. For the kid.
- For the kid. - Oh, you're a saint!
We thank you so much. Here you go.
Either leg. Or both! I don't care.
Maybe put a doodle on it. Doesn't need to be perfect.
He's also legally blind.
I put a little train there because I know you like trains.
Come on, come on, come on.
- Just, jiggle it... - Yes, I know.
- Hurry! - I got this.
Jiggle it, jiggle it, jiggle it!
Hopps and Wilde!
You are not authorized!
Stand down and wait for backup!
- Toot-toot. - It's the fuzz!
Stop! Stop in the name of the law!
Everybody, run!
Well, can't win 'em all.
Get outta the road, you dumb bunny!
Agree to disagree.
My hog rod!
This is a snoutrage!
Hopps and Wilde in pursuit of suspect in a stolen catering van heading east-
Stop it! Heading east through Sheepshire.
Beautiful!
I'll have what he's having.
Darlin', I believe your driving's giving me some white hairs.
Also, am I always gonna be in the passenger seat?
- Cause if we're establishing sides- - Back off, rookies!
Let the real teams handle it!
Ma'am, we are a real team.
Shortcut, take the tunnel.
Stand down, noobs.
We got him. Rolling spikes!
Rolling spikes.
I hate that dumb bunny.
I'm gonna jump.
No, no, no, what, what are you, you can't.
Hey, I would like to call a partner meeting!
You can't-
Judy!
Please, join me in a moment of silence
for our beloved weather wall inventor, Ebenezer Lynxley.
Zebros!
Reptile.
Zootopia ain't just a mammal city.
It has a secret tiny reptile population.
The most live abroad.
Of course, Zootopia does not allow snakes.
Ain't been one of those around here for at least 100 years.
Scales and Tales of the Weird!
Yeah, not sure Nibbles Maplestick is our most reliable source.
Bunny, orange dog, in here now.
Sir, today may not have been ideal, but the anteater was captured.
- By the Zebros! - Zebros!
- Shut it! - Zebros.
It was us.
But more importantly, I believe we may have made a significant discovery.
The stolen van contained a smuggled crate from overseas, pamphlets for the Zootennial
and some type of reptile skin.
I've already sent samples for testing. And-
What needs testing is you!
You two tore up half the city!
Because of you, we had to call in Jumbo Unit to remove a dik-dik from a tuba!
- You're almost out! - Please help! Please help!
- Who's catching him? - Sorry,
could you show me that clip again?
Wasn't wearing my glasses.
Did you or did you not disobey a direct order to stand down?
Sir, we were in pursuit, and Article 6, Paragraph B states if the lead officer-
You are not lead officers!
You're one-hit wonders who should go back to meter maiding and slinging popsicles!
If I may, I think someone's just jealous that we got to drive the squeal mobile.
Or maybe you thought it was your mama.
Enough! Everybody, out!
Officer Hopps, despite my best efforts to avoid it,
I like you.
But this need to overdo it
made both of you a headline today.
And it reflects badly on me, on the department, and frankly, on any bunny
hoping to follow in your footsteps.
Not every case is going to save the world.
Knock, knock.
Hi.
You know this kinda, this sounds a lot like a, just a you guys conversation.
So what I'm going to do is I'm going to go ahead-
Is there a reason why you don't take anything seriously?
Jokes are a classic defense mechanism for someone with a traumatic childhood.
Would you like a traumatic adulthood?
I would not.
I allowed you to work together because you did this city a great service.
But today you messed it all up.
And now, some are questioning whether you should have been partners
- in the first place. - But, sir...
So instead of chasing imaginary reptiles, I am pulling you from the field.
- What? - And giving you a new assignment
reserved for special teams like yourselves.
Fail at this, and I will have no choice but to split you up.
There will be no more Hopps and Wilde.
But if you're good as you think you are, this is your moment to shine.
Welcome to Partners in Crisis, a workshop for duos heading for disaster.
I'm your therapy animal, Dr. Fuzzby, and you are here because
mismatched pairings often need a little more work to make them work.
Greg? We talked about that.
What are we making Marlon? Uncomfortable.
Yes.
And Francine, Clark may be a mouse, but he is your partner first.
And we have two new partners.
Can you tell us about your journey to dysfunction junction?
Well, we've been official partners for one week, happy anniversary.
And we are not dysfunctional at all, actually.
Functioning fine, better than fine.
And we did sorta save the city.
So, us being here kinda seems like a huge misunderstanding.
Notice how she answered first, did not allow her partner to speak,
seems to be in a state of denial, and taps her foot
when she's suppressing discomfort.
And observe the source of her discomfort,
represented by the disconnected affectation
of her emotionally insecure partner.
But with hard work, they'll be on the same page by year two!
But for now, let's begin by greeting our teammate.
Who'd like to go first? Thank you, Joel.
Okay, unfortunately, Karen has chosen
to see Joel's smile as a sign of aggression.
Hackles down, Karen.
Karen, hackles down.
Joel, the safe word is "coconut!"
Coconut!
Okay, we have to set another meeting with the chief.
Promise we'll be better.
Zebros...
You talk back less. Maybe not at all.
Yeah, or we go with my playbook and we just lay low.
We cannot prove ourselves if we are stuck in that room.
And if we complain to Chief Beef, he'll just make us stay longer.
Play it smart, stay off the radar, and don't let it get to you, okay?
Cause we are the dream team.
Sorry, Paul.
Oh, roll out the red carpet.
Here's the Supercops.
Wait, hey, what does the fox say?
- You suck. - Easy, partner.
Let me ask you something.
- Do you think we're a good team? - Of course.
I just... I just wish I knew what we had to do to prove it to everyone else.
Or maybe we don't have to prove anything to anybody.
We do.
Forever.
And the sooner everyone sees a fox and a bunny can be great partners, the better.
Enjoy it. I got two.
I'd rather chew off my own arm.
Happy anniversary!
Coconut! Coconut!
So, saw you on TV. You okay?
- Everything's fine, Mom. - Uh-oh.
Everyone knows fine is a cry for help.
You know who else cried for help?
That dik-dik stuck in that tuba.
Oh, him and the dik-dik.
What does your fox partner say?
Well, Nick's not really a talker.
Well, you two are very different.
Small town hero, raised on a farm.
Big city crook, raised on the streets.
I pray every day that you'll
- come back home and make babies. - Mom!
Just remember the first rule of partnerships.
- You can be right or you can be happy. - That's true.
There's nothing wrong with dying a little inside so you can meet in the middle.
Honey, you're pushing me out.
I want to make sure I can be seen.
- Well, if she could see both of us. - Okay, gotta go!
- Work to do. - Bye, bun-bun.
Everything's gonna be fine.
- You two just need a new case. - Got it. Love you!
- Hey, maybe try to find that dik-dik! - Bye!
Ding-ding-ding-ding-dingeringeding! Gering-ding-
Squeal of Fortune!
Tomorrow's weather is, again, everything!
To announce that the long-awaited Tundratown expansion will be starting soon.
Residents continue to raise concerns about the future of their neighborhood.
But tonight, we put our differences aside and celebrate at the Zootennial Gala,
where the Lynxley Journal will be on display for the first time
in a century, following an infamous reptile attack.
The Lynxley Journal, containing the patented weather wall plans,
was originally written by Ebenezer Lynxley, bringing the whole-
Same catering company.
The Lynxley Journal.
Truth bomb!
The 100th anniversary of the weather walls is also the 100th anniversary
of Zootopia's only snake attack.
The victim? A tortoise.
The Lynxley family maid, who was fanged while stopping
a venomous snake from stealing the Lynxley Journal.
No one has seen a snake in Zootopia since, but I'm convinced one will return.
My only question is, is he going to be wearing half a pants or one long sock?
You say justice is dead.
I say, neigh!
Well, well, you missed me already, huh?
The stolen van with the snake skin
is from the same catering company that's working the gala.
- This is you studying your partner book? - Listen to me.
Venomous snakes tried to steal the Lynxley's journal before.
What if they're back in town to steal it again?
No snake has set foot in Zootopia in forever.
Okay? Even if they had feet.
Look, we're already in the hot seat, Carrots.
And pizza's here. Gotta go-
If there's a fanging at the gala and we do nothing to stop it,
then we are not doing our jobs.
Yikes.
No wonder you never invite me over.
Foxes are solitary.
And look, we go and you're wrong, Chief Beef will split us up.
And if we don't get a win soon and prove we're great partners,
the chief will split us up anyway.
Check the perimeter, snoop a little.
We find nothing, we bail.
But if I'm right, no one will question whether you and I belong together again.
We need this.
Fine.
But we'll still have to get through security.
And in fancy town, a fox and a bunny won't exactly blend in.
That's why we'll be undercover!
See, you're still in the driver's seat.
♪ Come on, get on up We're wild and we can't be tamed ♪
♪ And we're turnin' the floor into A zoo, ooh, ooh ♪
Here we go. Here we go.
Let's go!
Zootopia, let me hear you!
♪ We live a crazy world, caught up in a rat race ♪
♪ Concrete jungle life is sometimes a mad place ♪
♪ It's you and me together at the end of a wild day ♪
♪ Don't keep it all bottled up and release your energy ♪
♪ Hey, oh-ayy, only reason we are here is to celebrate ♪
♪ in a place where anyone can be anything ♪
♪ Hold on to this moment, don't let it fade away Baby, keep the music playin' ♪
♪ Come on, get on up We're wild and we can't be tamed ♪
♪ And we're turnin' the floor into A zoo, ooh, ooh ♪
♪ Come on, keep it up It's fun if you're down to play ♪
Oh, cats and lights. I know better!
♪ A zoo, ooh, ooh ♪
♪ Come on, get on up We're wild and we can't be tamed ♪
♪ And we're turnin' the floor into A zoo, ooh, ooh ♪
Mayor Winddancer has arrived.
- Star of the Revenge Trilogy, The Neighsayer. - No pictures, please.
Come on. And that, and that one, and then this one.
Mr. Lynxley, Mr. Lynxley! When will you begin the Tundratown expansion?
- Come on, Dad. - Have a wonderful time at the party.
♪ It's fun if you're down to play ♪
♪ And we're turnin' the floor into A zoo, ooh, ooh ♪
No snow.
This one's warmer.
Reptile in Tundratown might need that to survive the cold.
Oh my God, a viper!
A window viper. Yeah?
Backdoor ajar.
Anyone could have left it like that.
And you said snoop a little, not break and ent-
Oh, we were always going inside. Got it.
Same page means your page.
It's called a hustle, sweetheart.
You change out here. I get the van.
It's the Zootennial Gala, a bunny comes prepared.
You know I used to dream of infiltrating a place like this.
You know, this is not your worst idea.
Wow, that was almost a compliment.
Your worst idea is what you did with your ears.
Alright.
Welcome to the Zootennial Gala. Featuring the original Lynxley Journal.
Why would a snake want to steal some old book anyway?
I don't know.
But no one is gonna steal it because we are here to protect it.
The journal is in the reserved section.
Okay.
- Come on. - Slow down.
You want to fit in? Commando is not gonna cut it.
It's not just the clothes, mkay?
It is the vibe.
Good to see ya.
Hey, real nice humps.
Oh, is that real mink? It's real fox.
Get invited to a lot of these?
Invited? No.
But there's other reasons to hobnob.
Madam, excuse me. Is this yours?
Why, yes.
Well, allow me.
Clever fox. Ooh, there.
I don't think it has enough guards.
I'll get a closer look. Watch my six.
Bogo-alert.
Cover's made of metal.
Gruffalo Buffalo has joined the mix. Three o'clock.
- Oh, excuse me. - Oh no, sorry.
- I am so sorry. - Here, let me just, oh nope-
That belongs to you. I apologize.
Oh gosh, he hates me.
- Here. - Ah, you're my hero.
Well, I just like to be prepared for any possible scenario.
Which is not a weird thing to say at a party.
Well, I just mopped a spill with that guy's tail, so...
Paw!
Uh, Pawbert! I am Pawbert! Hi.
- Judy. I'm Judy Hopps. - Ah, what the pork?
Well, 'tis nice to meet you Judy-
Wait, Judy Hopps, the Judy Hopps?
Are you working this?
I mean, you're clearly working it.
But are you actually working this?
Uh, no. I'm actually-
Well, it's just a hunch.
Protecting that.
Good. I don't think it has enough guards.
Uh, that was my joke.
And you know... And there's nothing here.
Let's call it a night. Hopps?
Well, we should...
It was nice to meet you.
Yes, and you,
Uh, bon appétit!
If at any point tonight you choose to eat, bon appétit then.
You're supposed to be off stage, Pawbert.
- Yeah, get off stage, Pawbert. - Wait are-
- Are you? - Yeah, I am a Lynxley.
Or, you know, I'm trying to be.
Now, Pawbert. Come on, Pappy.
- I got you, Pa, don't you worry. - No, I have him.
I have him.
All right, let's get this thing started.
- Welcome to the Zootennial Gala. - Hey, Hopps.
I think I might actually...
I think I've got something!
Look at you all.
Good to see you.
It is with great pleasure that I introduce the third generation...
Carrots, can you hear me? I have a trail.
-the legacy of our great city, Milton Lynxley!
- Thank you. Thank you - Carrots.
- very much. - Carrots!
What are you doing here?
- Chief, she was right. - You're done.
You're both done.
My grandpa had a dream to build
- a city for all of us... - Nick?
To truly be better together.
There's a snake!
Snake, snake, snake!
Go, go, go!
I will remember you, zebra!
Judy! Judy!
I knew it!
Stop!
Please, you don't have to hurt him.
Hurt him?
Snakes never hurt anyone.
We aren't the bad guys.
They are.
And this journal holds the secret that will prove it.
I have to prove it. Please.
This is our only chance to set things right.
And when I do, my family will finally be able to come home.
Oh no!
I am here!
Hopps and Wilde, dream team. We got him.
Or her. Reptiles, it's like, who knows?
The cops are right behind us.
Kill the snake.
We'll burn the journal.
If he wants it, it's dangerous.
And then you two will file a report that he attacked us
and you will keep your mouths shut.
Step aside.
Put out the fire!
- Carrots, come on! - Help me save him!
- Carrots, we need- - Nick!
Cold! Cold!
Chief.
He'll be okay. Anti-venom.
- He can be saved with anti-venom. - Hopps!
What did you do?
- Hoggbottom! - They're helping the snake!
They're trying to kill the chief!
Hoggbottom, no, please-
- My page. Let's go. - Wait, wait, wait, I need the journal!
And probably a sweater!
Cold!
- Next time, we stay home? - Don't you...
No, stop them!
- Oi! Wait! - Come on, come on.
Stop!
- I really am just a dumb bunny. - Accident.
Your words, not mine.
Put 'em in the trunk.
What?
Ter-roar in Tundratown!
A fanging at the fiesta.
A hooowl at the gala as a venomous snake attacks the founding family.
More shocking, the snake was aided by embattled ZPD officers
Nicholas Wilde and Judy Hopps.
All three now suspects in the tragic fanging of Zootopia's chief of police
and considered extremely dangerous.
Chief Bogo is dead.
Those are words I'm glad I don't have to say.
I might have to soon
the doctor's a little weirded out, but what has happened tonight
was more than horseplay!
We're gonna take that snake down.
And the fox and that rabbit.
Do you know how many mayors they've already destroyed?
One... Two...
I got up to two.
Would you like to be three?
I want them gone.
But aren't there laws?
I will say this once, Brian.
You will retrieve the journal and bury them.
Or maybe I chose the wrong mayor.
Did I choose the wrong mayor?
Hey. The phone is the first thing they'll track.
Sorry.
I have never been on the run from the law before.
Yeah, boy.
It's almost like we shouldn't have gone to that gala.
Okey-doke, we already did it your way.
With Mr. Big, we do it mine.
This is where having a partner from the underworld is really gonna pay off.
Raymond! And is that Kev-
Welcome to my warehouse!
Oh my God, I love your dress!
Oh, thank you.
Fru Fru and I are now equal partners in the family business.
She brings wonderful ideas for crime and for fashion
while I get more time to focus on what matters most,
being grandpapa to my little Judith.
Kiss my ring.
- Kiss the stinking ring right now! Kiss it! - Kiss it right now! Kiss it!
Nonno, you said we were gonna make some nice shoes for Mr. Weaselton.
- That's my girl! - They grow up so fast.
- You run your mouth too much! - Shut your mouth, fox!
Anyways, you're in trouble, and we like... one of yous, so we're here to help.
New clothes, new identities, truck out of town, leave in an hour,
and your meter maid car is taken care of.
I think you misunderstand.
We've been framed by the lynxes and an innocent snake-
Judy, the lynxes are killers, and they have no honor.
And this Tundratown expansion only makes them more dangerous.
Territorial animals will do anything for more land.
So if whatever you're tangled up in threatens their plans, you're dead.
You don't fight the cats.
You leave.
Sir, I know you're trying to look out for us, but we took an oath
to protect this city, and justice doesn't run!
On behalf of myself, Rick Wilde and Ms. Trudy Cabbagepatch.
We thank you for your truck to salvation.
We cannot accept your offer.
We are helping that snake.
Boy, you're really tossing that 'we' around.
Snakes may have been framed for the fanging of that tortoise.
Do you have any idea why or how this book could prove it?
I wish I did.
But if it has to do with snakes, your best bet is talking to a reptile.
Do you know any?
Almost no one does.
They keep to themselves, hide out in Marsh Market.
But you can still find them.
You just need a reptile expert, someone local who knows where to go.
Lucky for you, I met someone.
She runs a podcast.
No, no.
Trudy Cabbagepatch.
Rick Wilde says no.
Oh, yeah!
Hopps and Wilde are on the lam.
Subtle sleuthing, 'tis my jam!
Mind the splinters. Oh, you called the right beaver.
If you want to talk to a reptile, I am your gal.
Also, if you need to talk to a jackalope, which are real, Mom!
Excuse us. Team meeting.
Vetoing the beave, new vote,
all in favor of 'truck to being alive and laying low till this blows over'-bill?
I mean...
Hopps and Wilde do not bail on a case.
But she's crazy.
Probably lead poisoning from eating too many pencils.
Do you know a reptile who can tell us the hidden secret in here
why the lynxes framed the snakes?
24 hours. Sunrise tomorrow.
If we strike out, then we go into hiding, and Judy Cabbagepatch it is.
It's Trudy Cabbagepatch, and the safe word is "coconut."
In the darkness, of a dank underpass, they stepped into the vehicle
not realizing their lives were about to change.
Because we're gonna meet a reptile?
Because you're about to be best buds with Nibbles Maplestick!
Takes two to tango, but a threesome to be somethin'!
Let's find you a reptile and rock the swamp!
Breathe it in!
Now if any reptile would know the secret of that book
and why the snake wants it-
Hey, Johnny.
It's my lizard friend Jesús.
Why would a lizard hide here?
Well, when Zootopia was founded, the whole neighborhood
got cut off from the rest of the town.
Kind of on our own here.
Yeah, it's probably why reptiles like it.
They can just do their thing.
Plus, it's the only place in town you can get away with
wearing a shirt and no pants.
Loving tour time with Woodchuckles. Great call.
- We need her. - Oh, yeah.
Like a hole in the head. Bad timing.
Okay, to get to Jesús' hideout, we gotta take a ferry.
Just let me handle the locals.
Water folk tend to be a little stand-offish around landies.
Well, I've been hustling the streets since I was twelve.
I think I can handle a juggling seal.
Sea lion.
He's not from around here.
But coin's a coin.
Oh, no, change...
...is a choking hazard.
Well, honest mistake.
Do not do that!
Let's let Nibbles handle this.
Thank you, Judith.
Conversing with these beautiful sea creatures
is like talking to anyone a little different.
Just takes open and respectful communication.
- Hey Bub. - Hey Bub.
- Hey Bubba, hey. - Hey Bub, hey.
- Bub, Bub, Bub, Bub, Bub. - Bub, Bub, Bub, Bub, Bub.
- Hey Bub. - Hey Bub. Hey, Bub, Bub.
- Hey Bub, Bubbybub. - Hey Bub, hey Bub.
- Hey Bub, Bub. - Hey Bub.
- Seen Jesús? - Yup.
And now, we leave town.
Thank you for this.
Happy anniversary.
Oh? It's your anniversary?
♪ This is the night ♪
♪ It's a beautiful night, and we call it bella notte ♪
How are we gonna find them now?
Thanks, seal.
I'm sorry, I'm sorry!
Just a little farther.
Jesús and all the answers you'll ever need are right here at the end
of this very scary dark hallway.
Boy, this is so much better than sitting on a beach on Outback Island
sipping piña koalas.
We are not skipping town when there is an innocent snake out there who needs us.
He's got help.
His motorcycle buddy.
You are acting weird.
What is your problem?
Well, A, you railroaded me, and B, if you must know,
I have an aversion to reptiles.
What?
Oh, is my discomfort hilarious to you?
Y-No, you- I'm sorry, you're right.
We are partners, and whenever I'm uncomfortable
you are always very considerate of my feelings.
Look out, snake skin!
I'm slipping, I'm slipping, I'm slipping, hold the rail!
- Hold the rail, hold it, hold it. - I'm holding it.
- Stop pulling my ears! - Hold it, hold it!
- Never pull a bunny's ears! - Hold the rail!
I think the real mystery
is how you two ever solved anything!
Anywho, let's see what Jesús has to say about your journal.
Oh, and if he offers you food, accept.
Declining is a sign of disrespect. To all of them.
All of them?
Order up.
Hey, another drink.
So warm.
Whoops.
Keep it.
Jesús!
Allow me to introduce my friends,
this is Judith and Nicholas,
they are wanted fugitives investigating a snake mystery
and trying not to get murdered. May we sit?
Okay.
Oh I'm good, but these guys look hungry.
Thank you for meeting with us.
We believe snakes were framed for something in this journal
- perhaps pertaining to- - Eat first.
Talk second.
Oh.
Hey guys, they ate it!
Look at their faces!
I don't eat grubs.
Hermano, get me a scone.
Okay, okay.
Metal cover.
And what does that mean?
It means it's fancy.
It also means the secret you're looking for is probably right on the cover.
Somehow vipers can see things in the middle, even under the paint.
This is Ebonezer Lynxley's original journal for the weather walls.
Why would he hide a secret for a snake?
I don't know, but it must have been big cause a tortoise died for it.
I am guessing that it was a slow death.
The fanging didn't just change how folks saw snakes.
No mammals trusted any reptile after that.
That's why we all left.
And that's when the Lynxleys expanded Tundratown the first time.
And it's happening again.
The expansion is going here.
Marsh Market will be buried in snow.
We'll all get pushed out.
Those lynxes will get more land, and there's no way to stop them.
What if the secret hidden in here could?
Then I would say holding it puts the two of you in grave danger.
They tracked you?
Whoops.
It's the ZPD!
Follow me.
Come on.
Wait, why are you helping us?
You two saved this city once.
I reckon you can save it again.
And when you do, maybe everyone'll see we ain't that different.
Freeze!
I'm really sorry, but this is my family's only chance to come home.
Wait, we wanna help!
Wait, wait!
Come back!
There's no path. Take the docks.
What?
- Carrots! - Wait!
We believe you!
Nick, come on, come on.
Grab it!
I got eyes on them!
- They're heading for the tubes! - In pursuit.
- Hey Bubba. - Hey Bub.
- Hey Bub. - Hey Bub.
Go!
- Hey Bub. - Bye-bye.
One tip.
If he goes for the red line, do not follow!
You will run out of air. Good luck.
I love you!
Cannonball!
No, that's a red line. Red line, red line!
You're gonna run out of air!
Coconut, coconut!
Anything you need, I got 'em!
Sequels, prequels, requels.
Who says the industry's going down the tube?
- Are you okay? - Yeah.
Yes.
You?
Well, I-I feel like some...
Some sorries may be in order.
Nick, it's okay.
I know you didn't want to lose him on purpose.
Oh, not me sorry. No, no.
You sorry.
Well, now we kinda have no way to find him or stop the lynxes, so...
Agree to disagree.
But we are alive.
So if we can't find him, that's great.
What we can find is a truck out of here.
Box of old matches. Helpful.
Trudy Cabbagepatch, leaving town. We're done.
Yodelay hee-hoo!
- This is weird place for you to be. - Ja, very weird.
You there fell out of the tube.
Okay, we will call police to help.
No! No, no, we're fine.
Yeah, but we were just leaving town.
Actually, um, do you happen to know where this tube goes?
- Copenhoofen. - Ja, is Copenhoofen.
Got it, thank y-
Ah, you chew too much, this is not-
Where did- Where did you find these flowers?
Oh, the Liebchen flower? At the tippity-top of the mountain.
This is only place they grow.
Oh, boy.
Is...
- Is there anything else up there? - Nope, there sure isn't.
Oh ja, old Honeymoon Lodge.
What is closed for a long time was hideout for snakes.
Honeymoon Lodge!
How- How do you reach it?
- Oh, tourist takes the tram from Copenhoofen. - But the rope is faster!
Good luck!
- Have fun at the Honeymoon Lodge! - Thank you!
What does this secret have to do with the reptiles leaving town?
How did it get hidden in the journal in the first place?
Will you slow down?
How long do you think it's gonna be before Hoggbottom and the ZPD
figure out where we are?
If anything, we should be going faster.
As I always say...
I really am just a dumb bunny.
Nick...
I-I-I really am ju- du-du-du- dumb bunny.
Just dumb-du-du-du-dumb bunny.
This was a gift.
To symbolize our partnership.
And it is not appropriate for this moment.
Oh, no, I was just-
Hoping to jot down some ideas for what we will put
on our tombstones. I'll start.
"His partner did it."
What happened to you that you can't just have a normal conversation?
I will save that for my therapy animal.
Yeah, you need a therapy animal.
Well, you need a herd of therapy animals.
Yeah, you need a whole migration of therapy animals!
Carrots?
Hey, Carrots?
Uh, Carrots?
Carrots!
There was a whole reptile neighborhood.
Their home.
The lynxes just erased it.
This is what they do.
We have to go.
They push animals out with lies so they can have more.
We gotta go, Carrots, we gotta go!
That's what the snake's trying to prove!
- The ZPD is here. - What?
No one will believe us. Not without proof!
Leave it! They aren't gonna just arrest us, the lynxes want us dead!
We need it, to solve the case.
- Judy, just- - We have to solve the case!
- Nick! - I don't care about the case!
Judy, it's not worth dying for.
The world will never be a better place if no one
is brave enough to do the right thing.
The world is what it is, Carrots.
And sometimes, being a hero
it just doesn't make a difference.
I think, uh...
I think...
Maybe, maybe we...
are different.
Oh my gosh, I think I just took out a cop.
Uh, sorry sir!
Pawbert?
Yeah, it's, you know...
- We're the good guys! - I told you she's helping.
Come with us!
We have the fox.
We have the fox!
They already have your partner.
They can't get you too.
Please.
We can stop my family.
Judy!
No, no, no!
I got you.
Alright.
Here we go.
You're not dead!
She's not dead!
Sorry! Sorry.
I just got my motorcycle license.
Nick?
They... They caught him.
But out here, no one's gonna catch us.
Mayor Winddancer.
Where's the bunny?
I don't know.
But you know, she's a rabbit, so maybe you can pull her out of your hat.
I'm not wearing a hat.
He's messing with you, sir.
I knew that. Get him out of here.
Where are they, Mr. Wilde?
Begin the expansion.
Freeze Marsh Market, flush everyone out.
No, you ca-
Water folk, like foxes, are lesser mammals.
If I say they helped a dangerous snake, no one will care what we do.
You're going to a dark cell, Mr. Wilde.
Just long enough to read the headline of your partner's demise.
You should have left town when you had the chance.
Dad.
Fur.
From whoever's helping the bunny and the snake.
Find Pawbert.
Almost to me hideout.
- Snake in the hole. - Yeah, yeah.
We shall succeed, Judy Hopps.
We'll stop the Lynxleys and save your partner.
I'm sorry. You are...
Gary. Gary De'Snake.
- And your last name? - De'Snake.
Everything is gonna be okay.
Teaming up with you is very exciting!
Don't worry about my fang.
I got my own anti-venom pen.
Stops the toxin.
Stab me straight into the heart!
Welcome to my oasis.
Away from my evil family.
I like to come here, just kinda veg out, get with all my cat stuff.
No! That's actually vintage.
And you could just not...
No, no, please don't.
- Wow, mammals get the best stuff! - Oh gosh.
- What's this do? - Wait! Not that.
Turn it off, turn it off, turn it off, turn it off. Turn it off!
So we should probably get to the journal.
How did you become partners?
When I found out the journal was gonna be on display at the gala,
I sent his family an anonymous letter asking to see it.
Luckily, they make Pawbert work in the mail room, so he read it first.
I got him smuggled in from overseas.
Seven days in a crate.
But if I fix things for my family, it'll be worth it.
Then we'll fix things for your partner, too.
Hey, I know coming with us was hard, but we're gonna help your partner
the same way we're gonna help the city.
We stop my family and show everyone the truth.
Are you ready?
Light the fire.
How much do you know?
Well...
That his family was framed.
And there's some secret hidden in the metal cover
that only a snake can see.
Not just any snake.
A heat-sensing pit viper.
All it takes is a little warmth.
I just don-
I don't understand.
Why would your great-grandfather hide a secret for a snake?
He didn't.
I...
It wasn't his journal.
That's the secret.
Zootopia wasn't created by a mammal.
It was created by a snake.
Gary's great-grandmother.
She wanted to make the city a place where all animals felt welcome.
So she invented her weather walls to help everyone.
She just needed an investor.
A partner.
But when my great-grandfather saw what her idea could be worth,
he plotted to steal her plans for himself.
So he committed a murder.
His own maid.
And framed Gary's great-grandmother.
And because she was a snake, everyone believed his lie.
Soon...
no reptiles were welcome.
And over time,
my great-grandfather buried the reptile neighborhood in snow.
And he died, believing no one could ever uncover his crimes.
But...
He was wrong.
Her original patent
was saved.
That's what you're looking for.
She hid it in her home.
Find her home, find her patent.
We just didn't know where her home was buried until now.
My family's land?
But under all that snow, how... How are we gonna find it?
Wait. Clock tower.
Her neighborhood, the reptile neighborhood, had a clock tower.
It lights up like a beacon!
If it wasn't fully buried, maybe we could see it.
Follow it to her home.
Except my great-grandfather turned off the power.
But we have the plans that show us how to turn it back on.
The power switch to her whole neighborhood was in...
- The original control room. - All right.
And where is that?
Inside the oldest wall of the city, the Desert-Tundratown weather wall.
We get inside, turn on that switch, light the clock tower - we find her house.
We find her patent.
And my family is finally coming home.
We will succeed, Judy Hopps.
We shall succeed!
I found him.
Get me Hoggbottom.
It's Nicholas Wilde.
Big time cop, huh?
I'll see you at the lunch table.
I'm gonna tie your tail in a knot!
- Hoggbottom? - What are you looking at, butt head?
Just- This is a mistake. It's a setup.
It's the lynxes!
Listen to me, please.
I know we have had our differences, right?
But, I-I've always respected you.
You don't respect anyone.
Phone. It's Milton Lynxley,
he's got the rabbit's location.
Whatever he says, it's a lie, Hoggbottom.
Hoggbottom, listen to me!
Nicholas Wilde!
What are the chances!
You know, this is my first time in prison.
And I gotta say, their food is on point.
How are you even here?
Destiny! Plus an arrest.
But it looks like Judith got away.
Was that decision mutual?
Oh, sensing in trouble in paradise.
Want to talk about it?
What I want is to get out of here.
Right, your big plan.
Lay low on Outback Island sipping piña koalas.
Except you can't trust koalas cause they got four thumbs.
Did a whole episode about it on the podcast.
It was called "They Got Four Thumbs." But you know what?
At least they ain't platypuses.
Wait, can you just, can you please just let me concentrate?
Roger that.
Just talk to me, dude.
What's the last thing she said to you?
She, um, she said,
"Maybe we are too different."
And what did you say before that?
I said the case isn't worth dying for.
Like... Like, you know,
as in it isn't worth her dying for because...
Because solitary animals like me don't have real friends.
And I... I...
I don't want to lose her.
So, I just...
I don't know how to say that.
You know what, bud?
I think you just did.
Wait, how'd you do that?
Well, I open my arms, put them around you, and then I squeeze.
It's called a hug.
Do foxes not have hugs?
Oh, the lock.
Yeah, that's Beave 101.
The rabbit's in Desert Dunes!
- Roll out! - Roll out!
Your partner needs you, and Nibbles Maplestick
is gonna get you to her.
Hey, it's the fox dad!
- And a woodchuck! - Woodchuck?
I'm a beaver! Call me that again-
Okay, go! We gotta go.
Here we go.
Hello, Nicholas.
I hope you like my new home.
I wove it with my own wool.
Jump scare!
Adios!
We're free!
Wheels. We need wheels.
No, no!
No, no, no, no!
I'm sorry.
I do not think we can get to Judy in time to help.
Unless...
You happen to know the fastest driver in the history of Zootopia?
Hey, Flash, Flash, Hundred Yard Dash!
Partner's in trouble, need to get across town, ignore the laws.
No...
problem.
Let's hit it.
Hey, glad you're here.
I got to tell you, I'm not convinced a sloth is our most reliable-
To turn on the clock tower, and light the way
to your great-grandma's home so we can find her patent, we need to reach
the power control room, through here.
But we have to move quickly or we're never going to-
We shall succeed, Judy Hopps.
Look, Gary, if we don't overprepare, we're underprepared.
And I don't...
My family has been trying to prove we're not what everyone thinks for 100 years.
But even this close, they never want me
to put the weight of the world on my shoulders.
Because, I don't have any shoulders!
We shall succeed.
I got you, rabbit.
I cannot help Judy if I don't know where she is, which is why I need you
to get on Paul's computer and track Hoggbottom.
You are an escaped fugitive.
I could get fired for even talking to you!
They're gonna put her to sleep! Do it!
Okay!
Did you try restarting it? Mm-hmm.
- Have you tried not being an idiot? - Hey, Paul.
I got you some donuts-
- Oh, no. - Thanks, Clawhauser.
Clawhauser! Location.
Oh, no.
I think we're gonna have to go through the festival.
Festival?
The phone's the first thing they track!
Go, go!
- Clawhauser! - I am working on it!
- Got it! - Great! Great, great.
- Now... - No!
What festival is this?
Come on! Go, go, go!
We are with you, Judy Hopps.
We meet again, zebra.
Here come the horns!
She's going for the door.
She's going for the door!
Clawhauser, we're out of time!
I got it!
Desert-Tundratown weather wall, access door.
Desert-Tundratown weather wall access door, hurry!
What is in that wall?
A power control room.
But for... like some old part of Tundratown.
I know what they're doing.
They'll ruin us!
No more tranquilizers!
- Put them down. - Sir?
Put them down now!
Take the shot.
Take the shot!
Do it!
Judy!
Power control room?
Uh, five flights up. Come on, hurry!
There is a lot of stairs.
Way to hustle, bud, I love you, I owe you!
It's turning on. It's turning on!
Nibbles?
Nibbles!
Snake!
Cold!
- It's jammed! - Don't worry about me.
Find the switch.
No, no, no, no, not these.
It would be...
Older.
Can you see it?
Did we turn on the clock tower?
There.
It's there.
We did it.
We can find the original patent.
Nick?
The door.
It's locked. Wait...
How did it lock?
Nibbles?
Open it!
Nibbles!
Dang door stuck on me.
Sorry.
Last case there was kind of a twist.
I know.
Oh my gosh, I really...
Oh, my heart is pounding.
Oh, I thought you knew.
I thought you knew.
Sorry, partner.
Hate to leave you out in the cold.
But, I'm gonna...
Please don't be mad at me.
But, I mean, you get it.
We've always been on the same page.
Me and you.
Underdogs, right?
You gotta prove you're as good as everyone else.
That you belong.
I know it's messed up.
But, this is my chance.
I have to take it.
Cause when I get to his great-grandma's home
and I burn the original patent,
I'll finally be something in my family.
And I'll finally belong, too.
Judy!
Carrots?
No loose ends.
Bye, partner.
Bye, Judy Hopps.
Pawbert. Please.
You can be different than your family.
I don't want to be different.
Nick.
Judy?
Nibbles, do you see her?
No, nothing yet.
Judy!
Ni...
We shall... succeed, Judy Hopps.
It's okay.
Judy sent me.
She needs to find Nick.
Yep. Should have seen that coming.
Judy?
Nick...
We...
shall...
succeed.
Judy.
I can't... move.
And you're too cold... to... help.
And he's gonna...
Nick's gonna...
Judy.
The world...
was never...
meant...
to be...
on one animal's... shoulders...
That's why my great-grandma...
wanted... Zootopia...
to be... for...
everyone.
So, we could...
all... help each other.
I... didn't... help.
You did.
You chose... to help...
me.
And became...
my best...
warm-blooded friend.
Very warm.
Permission to hug?
We're gonna save you.
And save your friend.
Judy!
Hey! He's gonna eat that rabbit!
No, I... Wait!
I-I'm saving her!
I'm gonna get her the anti-pen!
Where is she?
She...
She didn't make it.
But with snake bites you go fast.
You'll see.
No!
She's gone, Nick!
Just, get it over with!
You're done.
Know when to quit!
Anti-venom!
We can save her with the anti-venom!
Throw me the bag!
Judy!
Leave it!
You're gonna kill us both.
It's not worth dying for.
Agree to disagree.
Stab me straight into the heart!
- I was trying to get to you... - I thought that you...
He told me that you...
- I saw you... - That you were...
I'll... help your friend.
Okay, I don't- I don't care that we're different. You know? I...
What I care about is you.
I care about you.
Okay?
And I didn't say it.
I should have said it, but I didn't because...
Well, cause I am an emotionally insecure
source of your discomfort
who is not good at expressing his feelings.
Probably because I've been on my own my whole life.
It's not an excuse.
It's just... It's why instead of telling you that you're
the best thing that ever happened to me,
I-I make jokes about your ears, and
and I tell you that you try too hard when, you know, the truth is I just don't want you
to get hurt, because...
Because no one else in the world
matters more to me than you do.
I... I do try too hard because deep down I'm afraid
that I am what everyone thinks I am.
And I suppress my discomfort because I'm worried it makes me look weak
and I want to be strong, and I think I'm failing all the time.
And I only take what you say personally because you're the only one in my life
who ever believed in me, even when I don't even believe in myself.
And I should have told you that.
No one else in the world matters to me
more than you do either.
I have unresolved childhood trauma that I refuse to discuss
because being vulnerable scares me.
I make dangerous choices because I have an unhealthy bunny hero complex.
And I didn't join the ZPD because I wanted to be a cop.
I joined because I always wanted to be part of a pack.
And the thought of losing you scares me because...
Because you're my pack.
I should never have left you.
And I do need a herd of therapy animals.
And I should have told you that you are
the only partner I would ever want because...
You're my fluffle.
That's a bunch of rabbits.
Now that is what we call an overshare.
I'm alive, by the way. I made it.
Oh, also, that guy's still alive.
Hey! Thief!
He's gonna get to the lost reptile neighborhood
find great-grandma's patent, and destroy it.
Yeah, I've got no idea what that means or who Gary is, but let's go!
Hopps and Wilde?
Wilde and Hopps!
And Nibbles and Gary!
He's Gary.
Thank you. It's for the snake. He's cold.
- No fur on him. - Where are you going?
Bye now!
- You! - Whoa! Dad!
- You don't belong in this family. - Wait, wait, wait! Dad!
- You will never belong in this family. - Wait, wait, wait!
I wasn't working with them.
I was helping us.
I know where the reptile neighborhood is buried, where to find the real patent
that proves that snakes invented the walls.
I'm gonna destroy it for the family.
For you, Daddy.
You want to keep your job.
You say nothing.
You!
Maybe you are a Lynxley.
Take me to the patent.
Takes a threesome to be somethin', but a four-way to bust your doorway!
Get to the patent!
Destroy it!
Go! We got this!
Hi, Whiskers. You're done
hurting my city.
Uh-oh, tides have turned.
Hey, Brian Winddancer.
You want to be a hero or just play one on TV?
I go left, and you go right?
Uh, yeah.
Or...
You are a horrible driver!
Yes, I am!
I'm gonna jump!
Zoogetherness!
No, never mind. Forget I said it. Here we go.
Matches, matches, matches, matches!
Bunnies, we're burrowers. Rabbit kick!
I'll destroy the patent,
that town and everything in it.
And a dirt bag fox and a dumb bunny will never stand in my way.
She's not a dumb bunny, and you're forgetting one thing.
What's that?
We're friends with a snake.
Howdy, partner!
Heads up!
- Daddy! - Daddy is busy!
Brian! Go!
You say justice is dead.
I say, neigh!
Here, kitty, kitty!
- It's called an arrest, sweetheart. - And boom.
No one will believe you over us.
We've always been better than you, and we always will be.
Nothing you do matters.
Well, it matters to him.
Shall we?
One long sock.
I'm gonna burn it all to the ground!
I'm a real Lynxley!
That'll do, pig. That'll do.
Astonishing news today.
After officers Judy Hopps and Nicholas Wilde, along with a pit viper
and a beaver, foiled another major conspiracy
by revealing the true inventor of the city's weather walls was a snake.
While the now disgraced Lynxley family were revealed to have stolen
the original plans and covered it up for decades.
You have not heard the last of Milton-
Their Tundratown expansion now officially canceled.
Some are calling you the dream team.
How did you do it?
Well, there's a lot of different animals out there and,
and sometimes we start to look at all the little reasons
that we're not the same, and it makes us worry.
But maybe if we just talk to each other, if we just try to understand one another,
we would see that our differences don't really make any difference at all.
Maybe we'd even see that what makes me, me, and you, you,
can make us even stronger.
And with hard work, you're gonna get to that by year two!
Yeah.
Zebros.
Actually, my name is Gene.
My name is also Gene.
Zebros!
He did it!
Kids, get off the snake.
How's everybody doing?
One second.
This is my family.
Permission to hug?
Thank you.
Hey, uh...
I got you something.
Love you, partner.
But I am still me, so I'm only saying it once a decade.
Well, I'm gonna need that back.
I'll give it back to you
after our next case.
There's gonna be another case, huh?
Of course.
Because when you broke out of jail,
you also released 200 highly dangerous prisoners.
Worth it.
Any idea where you want to start?
One-way ticket to Outback Island, please. First class.
Very nice.
And remember, if you're happy with our service,
please be sure to leave us four thumbs up.
Oh, I will.
- Hopps and Wilde. - Wilde and…
Cabbagepatch.
Zootopia, vamos!
Burning Mammal, let's go!
♪ Come on, get on up ♪
♪ We're wild and we can't be tamed ♪
♪ And we're turnin' the floor into A zoo, ooh, ooh ♪
♪ We live in a crazy world, caught up in a rat race ♪
♪ Concrete jungle life is sometimes a mad place ♪
♪ It's you and me together at the end of a wild day ♪
♪ Don't keep it all bottled up, and release your energy ♪
♪ Hey, oh-ayy, only reason we are here is to celebrate ♪
♪ In a place where anyone can be anything ♪
♪ Hold on to this moment, don't let it fade away ♪
♪ Baby, keep the music playin' ♪
♪ Come on, get on up We're wild and we can't be tamed ♪
♪ And we're turnin' the floor into A zoo, ooh, ooh ♪
♪ Come on, keep it up ♪
♪ It's fun if you're down to play ♪
♪ And we're turnin' the floor into A zoo, ooh, ooh ♪
♪ A zoo, ooh, ooh ♪
♪ We live in a heated time, no chance to cool down ♪
♪ Continuously confined, and what do we do now? ♪
♪ It's all about finding love, sometimes hard to come by ♪
♪ But when it comes to us, it's always a good time ♪
♪ Hey, oh-ayy, only reason we are here is to celebrate ♪
♪ In a place where anyone can be anything ♪
♪ Hold on to this moment, don't let it fade away ♪
♪ Baby, keep the music playin' ♪
♪ Come on, get on up We're wild and we can't be tamed ♪
♪ And we're turnin' the floor into A zoo, ooh, ooh ♪
♪ Come on, keep it up It's fun if you're down to play ♪
♪ A zoo, ooh, ooh ♪
♪ Zoo, ooh, ooh ♪
♪ I'll take you higher, I'll take you higher ♪
♪ We can't be tamed, baby, I'll take you higher ♪
♪ Es una fiesta que sube como la espuma ♪ (It's a party that's going off like crazy)
♪ Yo por ti iré hasta la luna de ida y vuelta ♪ (I'd go to the moon and back for you)
♪ Come on, get on up We're wild and we can't be tamed ♪
♪ And we're turnin' the floor into A zoo, ooh, ooh ♪
♪ Come on, keep it up It's fun if you're down to play ♪
♪ Come on, get on up We're wild and we can't be tamed ♪
♪ And we're turnin' the floor into A zoo, ooh, ooh ♪
♪ Come on, keep it up It's fun if you're down to play ♪
Love you, partner.
Hey, bunny, you gonna keep playing that all night?
Leave her alone!
She's proud of herself but still seeks external validation!
Oh, shut up!
- You shut up! - You shut up!
Hey, bunny. What's next for you two?
Uh, we're investigating a rabbit who strangled her neighbors!
- You offended her! - You offended her!
Shut up!
- Good night! - You shut up!
Subtitles by Shincosutan.